the goal for most home gym owners is to
find themselves a true centerpiece so if
that's the situation you're in you might
want to consider the rep Fitness PR 5000
it's made from 11 gauge steel it can
hold up to a thousand pounds of weight
oh and it's completely customizable I've
been using this rack for a while now and
there's a whole lot to talk about so
kick back relax and hang out with me for
a little bit as I break it all down
what's up y'all it's Jake back in the
barbin garage gym and for today's video
I've got the rep Fitness PR 5000 in for
review in this video I'm going to tell
you every single thing you need to know
about this power rack from the price and
the features some pros and cons you may
run into and of course who should or
maybe should not purchase one of these
now before I dive into all of that I
have to let you know we've reviewed a
ton of power racks on barbin.com so if
you want to browse our best list just go
and search bar band best power racks
it'll pull right up for you and you can
find out for yourself which ones that we
like the best
all right so let's talk about some of
the things I like about the pr 5000 and
remember you know once again it is made
from 11 gauge steel and it has a weight
capacity of a thousand pounds so unless
you're in the 99th percentile of
athletes this rack is going to be
perfect for you and you're really going
to be able to grow with it over time
once again it's completely customizable
so you can decide what size you want it
to be the color scheme and even the
attachments I'm going to dig into all
that in just a second don't worry but
let's talk about the size first so you
have two different height options we
went with 80 inch version there's also a
93 inch version and you have three
different options in terms of depth
whether that be 16 inches 30 inches or
41 inches so you know if you're really
tight on Space maybe go after that 16
inch option and you know it's probably
going to fit just remember though it's
not really going to be a true power rack
because you're not going to have a cage
to work within so definitely you know
just keep that in mind now my personal
favorite attachment with the pr5000 is
hands down the Aries and anybody who
doesn't know what the Aries is it's
essentially going to add a cable machine
to your power rack so you're going to
have two different weight Stacks in the
back of the rack and you're gonna have
six different attachment points with
cables if that makes sense it's really
only four cables but the way everything
is set up you have six different
attachment points these cables operate
on a two to one ratio meaning the weight
you're lifting is actually half of what
is selected if that makes sense but cool
thing is that rep actually went ahead
and accounted for that both of the
weight Stacks are 260 pounds unless you
go for that upgraded version of 310
pounds and I really like how the rack
building feature lets you decide the
final price tag of your rack so that way
you can figure out your budget and stay
within it whenever you're building your
rack
all right now let's talk about a few
potential cons some people may run into
with the pr 5000 I want to talk about
price and size first yes you can
determine the final price tag of your
rack but you're at least gonna have to
spend eleven hundred dollars you know
that's without any of the extra
attachments so when you're building your
rack you have to choose between your own
version of a pull-up bar safeties and
Jacobs now if you were to go for the
cheapest option of all three of those
that's where you're going to be spending
around eleven hundred dollars so that
might be a turn off for some people
because this could be over six grand if
you were to go for the Aries and for all
the extra attachments so definitely keep
that in mind and let's talk about size
yeah I just talked about how it can
probably fit in a tight space you know
especially with that depth of 16 inches
but some people may just benefit from
having a rack that mounts on your wall
and can be folded so definitely keep
that in mind and let's talk about
assembly now it's going to vary
depending on you know your configuration
the size you want whether you want to be
a four post or six post obviously we
have a six post rack right here I
assembled this myself and guys it was a
grind I would say it took me at least 10
hours I say at least because I split it
up into two different days I kind of
lost track of time I sometimes enter a
Time Vortex whenever I'm in this garage
and like I said you know 10 hours that's
a long time I did it by myself you know
if I would have had some help it
definitely would have been cut down a
little bit White Glove assembly is going
to run you around 650 bucks if you were
to go for assembly with the Aries and
the actual rack itself 400 for the Aries
around 250 for the rack so definitely
just keep that in mind but at the end of
the day I think it's worth it just for
your own mental sanity if you don't want
to spend that money though I'd
absolutely recommend having an extra
pair of hands on deck just to make
everything go so much smoother and this
might not affect everybody but when
you're going to build your rack some of
the stuff may be out of stock whether
that be the color scheme or the
attachments themselves so definitely
keep that in mind let's talk about these
urethane D handles for a second too
they're a little bit underwhelming to me
personally they don't they don't have
any knurling on them and that's
something that I you know look for in
equipment so I'm gonna be upgrading here
soon and I also want to talk about the
landmine okay so the landmine attachment
is designed to go in this upright right
here at the base of it but because of
the pulley system it's simply can't go
there so that might be a bit of a bummer
for some people but you know in the long
run you're still going to be able to use
it where I have it positioned right now
and I think it's going to be fine it's
just not where it's supposed to be
okay so let's talk about price real
quick once again you're going to be
determining the final price tag with
your configuration of the pr 5000 but
you know the base value the cheapest
this rack is going to be is around
eleven hundred dollars Aries attachment
once again is about 2 800 bucks if you
were to go for Aries attachment you know
all the upgraded versions of the
attachments go for everything they have
available you're gonna spend over six
thousand dollars and white glove
assembly could potentially cost you
another 650 bucks so yes this could be a
very expensive purchase but the coolest
thing about it is that you yourself are
going to determine that final price tag
thank you
okay so let's talk about the build now
with the pr 5000 once again the uprights
are made from 11 gauge steel and they're
rated to hold up to a thousand pounds
which is a really high number that's
really solid so once again you have two
different height options to work with 80
93 inches you also have three different
options in terms of depth whether that
be 16 30 or 41 inches so it's really
cool you know you can completely
customize this to your liking you do not
have West Side spacing here so if that's
something you want I definitely
recommend going after the lower j-cups
that way you can mimic that style of
spacing so you're gonna have one inch
pinholes here with two inches in between
each individual hole there's 13
different attachments you can add on to
this rack I'll dig into that in just a
second and remember you know we built
our rack around the Aries attachment
which is essentially a cable machine
you're going to have two different
weight Stacks in the back of the rack
both of them equal 260 pounds unless you
spend 300 for that upgraded version I
forgot to mention that just a second ago
when I was talking about money but
definitely keep that in mind and
remember the cables operate on a two to
one ratio all right now let's talk
pretty briefly about attachments I'm
going to explain all this in just a
second but whenever you're building your
rack you're going to have to choose
between your version of pull-up bar
safeties and Jacobs after that though
the rest is completely up to you so for
me personally I wanted to go with the
dip handles and the landmine attachment
as well as the leg rollers that's just
me personally though I mean that doesn't
mean those are the best options out
there you know there's 13 different ones
for you to choose from so I would just
recommend you know going off of what is
going to suit you best and your specific
workouts
all right so I want to walk you guys
around the pr 5000 and just kind of
demonstrate how it operates for the most
part so
you have 11 gauge still uprights you
know these are rated to hold up to a
thousand pounds which is a really
impressive number so
this rack is going to be in it for the
long haul now I decided to go with the
multi-grip pull-up bar it's really
versatile you know you have a bunch of
different grips for you to work with and
it's you know it's pretty
straightforward you just pull up that's
why it's called a pull-up bar but um
yeah you know you have a two inch grip
back here and I really like how you
don't have to flip it around like you
did with the pr 1100 you're as long as
you have enough clearance above your
head you can just do your pull-ups
within here but if you are challenged in
terms of you know the height of your
ceilings in your home gym
this pull-up bar can actually be
inverted you can flip it upside down and
you know accommodate accordingly to your
ceilings which is really cool now I
decided to go with the flip down
safeties
they're really durable or solid Like a
Rock they also come with this pin right
here and it's going to help you know in
terms of just keeping everything locked
into place in case you were to drop you
know a loaded barbell with a bunch of
weight on it these aren't going to fall
out or anything and also aligned with
the same plastic that's on these round
sandwich Jacobs I decided to go with
both of which are going to help protect
your barbell and just prevent it from
being damaged now
let's move to the back really quick it's
the Aries attachment this is my favorite
thing about this power rack right here
as you can see you have two different
weight stacks back here I did not get
the upgraded version 260 pounds on each
side is plenty for me and it might be
for you as well
and this is just awesome so right up top
right here you have your lap pull down
here let me grab my weight bench really
fast and also I went with the leg
rollers
I I want to be able to do my split
squats with them and I need to lower
these down a little bit but
whenever you're not doing split squats
these are going to be great in terms of
keeping your legs down as you're going
to do your lat pull downs and it's
pretty straightforward you know just put
your feet underneath them
and then you just you know do your
workout and it's going to prevent your
body from wanting to go up especially as
you move up and wait now
you have this banana attachment right
here which is really cool in my opinion
basically you know your carabiners are
going to connect right here and if you
have you know triangle attachment or
maybe your own flat pull down bar that
isn't compatible with the Aries you can
make it fit on this right here which is
pretty cool I do wish they would have
had a banana attachment for the low row
down here but it's okay you can
definitely work around it now you can
adjust where this positioning is of this
foot plate there's a pin right here you
just pull up on it and you're able to
pull out I think there's four different
yeah there's four different adjustments
you can make that way you can be further
away from your cables or from your
weight Stacks excuse me if you want to
now this is actually a pretty nice
bar right here it's got a really nice
knurling on it both of these are made
from or Chrome plated excuse me and so
you're gonna have to clean them every
once in a while just to you know prevent
any rust if you're not in a climate
controlled environment but they're
really nice they have a really
impressive knurling in my opinion now
once again you know these are going to
be great for split squats and for
keeping your legs down but they do
wobble a little bit so definitely just
you know be cautious of that and I also
really like how
you have these extra weights you can
throw on here there's four of them
two on each side these weigh five pounds
so if you get into the problem of maxing
out just simply toss those on there and
you're good to go and this selector pin
is actually magnetized so you don't have
to worry about it you know falling out
as you're working out ignore how this is
a little crooked I'm not the best with
that kind of stuff but it's it's good it
gets the job done all right now let's
move to the front really fast I want to
talk about these dip handles I
personally really like these I love
doing dips when I'm working out it's a
great exercise for your chest and your
triceps and I read some stuff online
some you know customers talking about
how they felt like these wobbled a
little bit and weren't very stable I
personally haven't noticed that I mean
I'll show you right now you know I'm
sitting here
I don't feel anything whatsoever I think
these are really solid in my opinion
it's really easy to put them in all you
have to do
well okay I'm doing it reverse obviously
so I have to rotate it and pull it out
so you'll just stick this guy in right
here
make sure it goes all the way through
lined up in the same hole and then you
just twist it because you want these
little hooks I guess you could call them
to fit and that's going to prevent
you know your dip handles from coming
out which you definitely don't want that
let's talk about these pulleys right
here and this trolley the trolley is
really easy to move you have this pin
right here it's going to help you out in
terms of you know it's a security
blanket keeping it where it needs to be
might not necessarily need that but you
know some people are gonna like that
it's really easy you just pop it in
there same thing as with the safeties
now once again you have this pop pin one
hand simply just slide it up and down
it's really easy to do and I like this
knurled handle right here it gives you a
really nice solid grip just for the sake
of this video I'm going to put this back
in here
now
there we go now these pulleys rotate 180
degrees which is really cool you know
you can do so many different angles
whatever exercise you're trying to do
whether you're doing some flies whether
you're doing some tricep extensions some
bicep curls whatever you're trying to do
you can do so with these right here now
the only problem that some people might
run into is that you know you can't go
above
this plate right here or you know down
low either because of the bolt and
everything it's just not going to fit so
I think it's gonna be fine but some
people might find a way to find some
nitpicky thing to complain about and
that could be it right there now let's
drop down to the bottom really quick
I already mentioned this earlier but you
know this landmine attachment was
designed to be in this upright right
here at the base of it and because of
this pulley right here
you're not able to do that so it'd be
really cool if rep would accommodate for
that and there was a hole right here so
you could utilize this pinhole and put
the land mine where it needs to be now
you're still going to be able to get a
solid workout in where it is right now
but
as you can see this cable is going to be
rubbing up and you know right back and
forth against the attachment itself so I
wouldn't necessarily I'm not going to
keep this here when I'm not using it and
I definitely wouldn't recommend you do
that either but really straightforward
process you just toss your barbell in
there and you're able to do all your
favorite land mine exercises and if you
have a t-bar attachment you can attach
to your barbell I think that's a really
nice workout right there do some t-bar
rows which is pretty cool now
this is a really really sturdy and
stable rack but if you want to if it
makes you feel even more comfortable you
actually do have the ability to bolt
this to the ground so every single
upright has two maybe three two two
different spots where you can bolt this
bad boy into the ground but like I said
you know I don't think you're gonna have
to worry about it toppling over on you
or anything and lastly I want to talk
about the powder coat finish I have
right here on my Matte Black Version I
like it it looks really great in the
garage but you know because of that
powder coat it's really going to show
some more wear and tear than probably
any other option wood now I can't speak
on all of them because I haven't been
able to use every single color option
obviously but
it's definitely gonna show and it's not
gonna you know decrease the lifespan
it's not gonna you know prevent you from
doing anything with this rack don't
think that's the case but as far as
Aesthetics go you know that might not be
what everybody's looking for I
personally don't mind it you know it
shows that this rack has had use it
shows that you know I'm actually getting
in here and working out just definitely
just keep that in mind and obviously
there's a lot of bolts here I wish I
would have counted how many bolts I put
together by hand
but you know once again there's just a
lot going on so if you don't want to you
know deal with 10 hours of assembly or
so like I did I definitely recommend
going after that white glove assembly
all right so I wanted to bring you guys
over here to the computer just so I can
really demonstrate how to utilize the
rack building feature alright so click
on rack Builder which you already have
and you're gonna see on the screen it's
going to show a bunch of different
configurations that you could do which
is pretty cool but whenever you come
down here you're going to notice you
have five different options to choose
from you can do the Omni the Apollo half
rack PR 4000 5000 or you can do what we
did and go after the Aries attachment so
we're gonna click on build my Aries and
from here this is where you're gonna be
able to do everything it's got a 3D
experience which is really cool it's
gonna update in real time as you're
clicking on attachments color scheme
size whatever it's going to adjust
accordingly alright so we're gonna click
on configuration right here
we're gonna go to Aries and rack because
that's what we have all right
so click on the series we want the 5000
and then we're going for the style so
you can either go for the four post
which is basically how it is right now
or you can go for the six post that way
you can have a full actual rack now from
here's height like I said you have 80
inches or 93 inches we're just going to
build the one that we have so 80 inches
upright colors See this is what I was
talking about where some stuff might be
out of stock so orange and white are
both currently out of stock we have the
matte black so I'm going to click on
right now and as you'll see everything's
the exact same price
doesn't matter what color you click on
except for that clear coat option which
is you know
570 bucks everything else is around 460.
all right so
rack it up you know once again this is
where you can kind of get creative a
little bit you know you can go 16 inches
30 inches or 41 inches which is what we
have so cross member color same concept
see we don't there's no matte black
right now there could be in a week could
be in a couple days I don't know so
for the purpose of this video right now
I'm just going to click on metallic
black just for some consistency here
same thing with the weight storage
actually had does have matte black so
it's kind of funky you know some stuff's
going to be just out of stock whenever
you're going to do this same thing with
the weight storage cross member color
all right weight storage horns
all right now weight stack upgrade you
know yes or no it's pretty
self-explanatory whether you want you
know your weights to be 260 pounds or
310 pounds so we didn't do that I'm just
gonna click no for right now
logo plate cross member all right so
this is where price starts to really
come into effect so you go for the
standard option that's 120 bucks
basically if you're for the compact
that's basically right around a hundred
dollars so we're gonna we're gonna go
about this actually you know what we're
gonna keep going with what we have all
right so save it to the rack it's going
to adjust the price right away and as
you can see it's also adjusting the
actual rack itself you can actually turn
this a little bit too which is pretty
cool now all right we're just gonna go
back to standard all right cool it's
there go to the pull-up bar you have
five different options you know once
again you're dealing with some out of
stock issues this globe grip is a really
good option for anybody who wants you
know the most difficulty I guess you
could say with their pull-ups because
you have to actually you know grip those
Globes so it's called The Globe grip
it's going to increase your grip
strength and that's pretty cool now we
went with the multi grip that's my
personal favorite it's a pretty good
option this is raw 1.25 inch option
right here it's technically an upgrade
from the standard option it's got bare
steel and it actually does have a little
bit of a knurling on there a little
pitted texture as they call it so you
know just definitely keep that in mind
if that's something that you're looking
for anyways back to the multi grip
go ahead and save that to the rack go
down to the safeties same thing flip
down actually out of stock right now
they have a pin pipe option that's also
out of stock for so for the sake of this
video don't have a choice we're gonna go
with the strap safeties all right now
and Here Comes Your J cups remember
this rack does not have West Side
spacing so if that's something that
you're really interested in something
that you really want I definitely
suggest going after these lowered J cups
because
well first of all they're they're
cheaper which is pretty nice I think we
all like that but it's gonna mimic that
style spacing which is pretty cool but
we have the flat sandwich so I'm just
going to save that to the rack and now
we can move on to the next step so with
the Aries included right now we're
already sitting at pretty much 4 600 so
yeah that is pretty pricey but you know
you could build without that and that's
going to shave around 2 800 or so off of
your rack then you could also go for
those cheaper options of everything we
just went for and bring that price tag
down even more now
same thing with supply issues you know
the dip stations out of stock which is
actually different than what we have we
have the drop in dip handles rather than
the dip station so you can actually have
to go over to the attachment section of
their website to find that now
oops excuse me now let's go to the land
mine you know go and save that to the
rack and look it's going to pop up down
here at the bottom
and the same thing with the leg roller
that's going to pop up on here as well
and it's all just gonna you know and
change in real time so I'm going to save
these to the rack I forgot they also
have the option for these ISO arms a lot
of people refer to them as Jammers this
is a really good attachment if you're
looking for some explosive workouts you
know a lot of football players tend to
do those kind of workouts because you're
doing a lot of jamming people that's why
they're kind of called Jammers you're
mimicking that movement so you know if
that's something that you're interested
in then you know I definitely suggest
going after that it's going to be really
great for your pecs and your shoulders
but it is 600 bucks so we're not gonna
do that right now there's a band Peg
option you know if you're somebody who
likes adding resistance bands to your
bench press or your squatting you can
definitely do so which is pretty cool
um but we didn't do that we're also
going to click no but see there's a lot
of stuff that's out of stock right now
you can get a barbell tube stand to go
on the side and get a dual barbell
hanger there's a utility horn that
actually serves multiple purposes you
can use it as a leg roller if you want
you can store you know your resistance
bands if you have any chains you can
store those on that as well which is
just you know it's a pretty nice thing
right there there's a belt squat I kind
of wish I would have snagged the belt
squat but you know it has to go in the
middle of your rack and that kind of
just takes up some space but that's a
really that's some really nice variety
to your leg day that's something you're
interested in might be worth checking
out it's about 300 or so there's also a
wall ball Target it's gonna be great for
your medicine ball throws you have
something to you know Target you've been
to Amat which is pretty cool and you
also have your half spotter arms right
here which can go on the front of the
rack if you want to work outside of the
rack now like I said you know a lot of
this stuff is out of stock right now so
based off of just these couple of things
we're looking at around 4 800 or so but
just for the sake of this video let's go
and add some other stuff on here just so
you can see what I'm talking about in
terms of price and you know we're
already sitting here basically right at
six grand and that's without you know
even having the option of adding four
more attachments so definitely keep that
in mind you know
yes this can be an expensive purchase
but it also can be pretty cheap if you
go you know down that cheap route don't
go for any of this stuff and you go for
the cheapest option of the stuff that's
actually like essential when you're you
know building the rack now really cool
thing here you click on view your space
down here at the bottom and it's going
to pull up a QR code and you can scan
that code with your phone and then see
what it would look like in your personal
space with your camera on your phone
which is just really cool in my opinion
you know rep really thought about
everything when they were you know going
about this process and it makes it a lot
easier you know because so many people
have the problem of just not having
enough space in their home in their
garage in their home gym whatever
wherever it is
spacing is always an issue so it's
really nice that you know you can build
this you know use that QR code and see
where you need it to go and how it's
going to fit and what's going to look
like and all that good stuff which is
pretty cool now let's say you know all
this stuff's out of stock and you know
you want to add it another time well all
you got to do is just click on equipment
up here and you can go to Rack
attachments and you're going to find a
whole lot of stuff right here so
there's that dip station I was talking
about there's a land mine there's a leg
roller right here and a lot of these you
know most of these like let's talk about
this dip station you can choose this one
between the 4000 and the 1000 so the one
this is not compatible with the pr 5000
definitely keep that in mind same thing
goes with the landmine attachment
they're all different and that leg
roller which you know that's just that's
nice you know if you're not even getting
the pr 5000 you have some variety right
there as well and there's just a lot of
different things you can do right here
you know if you ever need to go back at
whatever time and add on more
attachments you definitely can do so and
so yeah that's pretty much it that's
pretty much my crash course thanks for
watching my TED talk when it comes to
the rack Builder it's just a really cool
feature and I think it's pretty unique
that rep is doing that
[Music]
foreign okay so when it comes to those
who might want to buy the pr 5000 it's
honestly pretty straightforward and
let's talk about the rack building first
you know because of all the
customization options this is a great
option for just about anybody because
odds are you're gonna be able to make
this rack fit in your personal space and
because of that you're going to be able
to determine that final price tag and
really work within your budget unless of
course your budget is less than eleven
hundred dollars and since it's made from
11 gauge steel and rated to hold up to a
thousand pounds this power rack is in it
for the long haul and it's one that you
can really grow with
foreign
now when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase the pr 5000 comes down
to three different things in my opinion
if you're looking for a rack that can be
moved around your personal space you
kind of want to you know switch up the
feng shui of your home gym you can't do
that with this rack it's way too heavy
trust me especially with the Aries
attachments talk about size too yes I
just got done saying you know you can
make this pretty small and odds are can
fit in your personal space but that's
definitely not a guarantee so you know
if you are really crammed on Space you
might be struggling when looking to add
this to your home gym and lastly it's
just the money you know yeah you do have
the ability to determine that final
price tag if you can't spend 1100 as I
just mentioned you need to look
elsewhere you know rep does have a
pretty nice power rack PR 1100s around
500 or so so definitely keep that in
mind as well
foreign
thanks for watching y'all I hope this
video was super helpful and that I was
able to break down every single aspect
of this power rack as always keep your
eyes peeled for my next video but for
now you know what I think you should do
in your meantime I think you should head
over to barbin.com and you know why
because we have a full written article
about this rack just waiting for you to
read all you got to do is search bar
band rep Fitness PR 5000 power rack
review it's going to pull right up for
you and you can read over every single
thing that I talked about here today
I'll catch y'all next time
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]